Guide to the Elizabeth Cone and James S. Cone Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Elizabeth Cone and James S. Cone papers
1898-1911
SC0609
Cone, Elizabeth Hiett.
Cone, James Stone.
3 Linear feet
Collection reflects student life at Stanford University and consists largely of photographs, including many cyanotypes; other materials include Elizabeth Cone's study cards, the constitution of the Saturday Night Club of Stanford University (women's debating club), programs, invitations, posters, and newspapers. Subjects of the photographs include the Quad and other campus buildings, views of campus lands, campus roads, the cactus garden, and students. Of note among the photographs are images of dorm rooms in Encina and Roble halls, female students in academic dress, the railroad tracks on campus, and Benjamin Blodgett, university organist.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Elizabeth Hiett Cone earned her A.B. in English at Stanford University in May 1901; while a student, she was a member of the Saturday Night Club. She died in August 1915. Her brother James Stone Cone earned his A.B. in history at Stanford in May 1902 and his M.A. at Harvard in 1905.
Description of the Collection
Collection reflects student life at Stanford University and consists largely of photographs, including many cyanotypes; other materials include Elizabeth Cone's study cards, the constitution of the Saturday Night Club of Stanford University (women's debating club), programs, invitations, posters, and newspapers. Subjects of the photographs include the Quad and other campus buildings, views of campus lands, campus roads, the cactus garden, and students. Of note among the photographs are images of dorm rooms in Encina and Roble halls, female students in academic dress, the railroad tracks on campus, and Benjamin Blodgett, university organist.
Access Terms
Blodgett, Benjamin Colman.; Cone, Elizabeth Hiett.; Cone, James Stone.; Moore, Dorothy Cone; Cyanotypes.; Photoprints.; Women college students.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Photographs:
    - Blodgett, Benjamin - organist (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cactus Garden (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Campus buildings (includes interior of foundry or shop) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Campus view, over Lake Lagunita (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Campus views (hills, lake, Roble Walk, railroad tracks, roads) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dogs on campus (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dorm rooms (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dorm rooms (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Dorm rooms, mounted images (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Dorm rooms with students (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Encina Hall (exterior) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Encina Hall residents on steps ca. 1902 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Escondite Cottage (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Football images (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Harrison planting tree on campus (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Hopkins Marine Station (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Jordan, David Starr (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Library, interior (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Mausoleum (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Memorial Church, exterior (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Memorial Church, interior (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Museum, interior (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Museum, exterior (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Palo Alto Tree (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Post Office on campus (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Quad arcades (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Quad arcades, mounted images (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Quad – East and West gates (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Quad Inner (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Quad – Memorial Court Archway (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Quad, miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Quad, mounted images (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Roble bridge (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Roble Gym (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Roble Hall (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Stanford buildings, etc., - prints from glass plate negatives (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Stanford Family Statue (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Students, off-campus – mounted images (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Students, on-campus – mounted images (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Students on campus (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Women students (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Non-Stanford images (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Alumni ephemera 1901-08 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - College songbook owned by E. Cone (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - E. Cone’s study cards and certificate of registration, 1898-1901 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ephemera 1899 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera 1900 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ephemera 1901 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ephemera 1902 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Illustrations and miscellany (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Invitation to Mrs. Jordan’s house 1899 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Saturday Night Club of Stanford University [women’s debating club] – constitution (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Stanford programs (Three Miracle Plays and Commencement) 1911 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 2 sets of mounted Stanford images strung on ribbon (hung in dorm rooms) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 2 scrapbook pages with 5 cyanotypes of Stanford images (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Empty scrapbook, red leather cover stamped “Stanford 1901” (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - two pieces of leather tied together as a binding, illustrated with a cupid figure on telegraph wires and the phrase “Take swift advantage of the hours” (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Daily Palo Alto issues Oct. 7, 1898 and April 15, 1902 (Box 4 os, Folder 1)
    - Poster for a frosh/soph tie-up (?) Oct. 29 [no year given]: “Clear the Track for Naw Teetoo and Get aboard the Train for the bleachers” (Box 4 os, Folder 2)
    - Page from Sunday Call “Romances of Stanford” by Sarah Comstock (about actual courtships and marriages of Stanford students) (Box 4 os, Folder 3)
    - Other San Francisco Call clippings and pages about Stanford events 1901-04 (Box 4 os, Folder 4)
    - Palo Alto Tribune. First Annual Edition and Rehabilitation Number (Volume II, Number 6) Friday April 19, 1907 (Box 4 os, Folder 5)
    - Poster for Field Day Rally in Assembly Hall April 19 [no year] (Box 4 os, Folder 6)
  - Photographs:
    - Encina Hall (Box 5)
    - Inner Quad (Portal) (Box 5)
    - Inner Quad (Portal) with shadow of photographer (Box 5)
    - Inner Quad, view of 3 arches toward what became Memorial Court (Box 5)
    - Inner Quad (Box 5)
    - Inner Quad, church entrance arches (prior to construction of church) (Box 5)
    - Front view of Quad, prior to outer Quad (Box 5)
    - Portal looking toward Inner Quad (Box 5)
    - Power house and chimney (Box 5)
    - Museum, front view (Box 5)
    - Original women’s gyn (Box 5)
    - Cactus Garden (see box 1, folder 2) (Box 5)
    - Campus view over Lake Lagunita (see box 1, folder 4) (Box 5)
    - Campus view over Lake Lagunita (see box 1, folder 4) (Box 5)
    - Campus view over Lake Lagunita (see box 1, folder 4) (Box 5)
    - Campus view, lake (see box 1, folder 5) (Box 5)
    - Dorm room (see box 1, folder 7) (Box 5)
    - Dorm room (see box 1, folder 7) (Box 5)
    - Mausoleum (see box 1, folder 19) (Box 5)
    - Mausoleum (see box 1, folder 19) (Box 5)
    - Quad arcade (with dog) (see box 1, folder 26) (Box 5)